

## **Shenin Francies**

Data Science | Medical Engineer

Detail-oriented Data Scientist, with strong analytical and technical skills, guided by the passion to work towards a unified cause. Recent graduate of Medical Engineering who conducts independent researches. Conversant in culture diversity due to exposure to international relations based off of studying and living in India, Kuwait, United Arab Emirates and Germany.

sheninfrancis23@gmail.com

Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala, India

Sheninfrancis23

+91 88 48 44 35 14

in linkedin.com/in/shenin-francies

github.com/SheninFrancies

#### **EDUCATION**

### Biomedical Engineering, MSc Hochschule Furtwangen University

09/2019 - 02/2022

Baden-Württemberg, Germany

Courses

Physiological Modelling

- Artificial Intelligence

EU Regulatory Affairs
 Artificial Organs

# **Electrical and Electronics Engineering, BEng.** Heriot-Watt University

09/2016 - 11/2019

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Courses

 Control Systems and System Theory MATLAB and Simulink

- C and C++ Programming

- Mechanical Design

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Intern - Data Science and Machine Learning Luminar Technolab

07/2022 - Present Kerala, India

Tasks

- Preprocessing of Datasets using Python libraries such as NumPy and Pandas.
- Applied Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning techniques on datasets to derive meaningful insights from the model.
- Familiarized with Deep Learning frameworks such as TensorFlow and Keras.
- Skilled in employing Data visualization tools such as Tableau and PowerBI.

#### **Research Assistant**

#### Hochschule Furtwangen University

08/2021 - 09/2021

Baden-Württemberg, Germany

Tasks

- Researched the Two- and Four-Electrode methods in Electrical Impedance Tomography.
- Built circuits and assessed the signal strength.
- Improved the circuit for optimal performance.

Contact: Dr. Alberto Battistel - baa@hs-furtwangen.de

#### **SKILLS**



#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Application of Deep Learning and Machine Learning (12/2022 - Present)

- .Scavenging data from the internet and employing ML/DL Techniques.

Applications of Machine Learning in Healthcare (12/2022 - 12/2022)

- Implemented Machine Learning algorithms to make predictions on various healthcare datasets.

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Applied Data Science with Python - Level 2 (11/2022 - 12/2022)

IBM

Big Data Foundations - Level 2 (11/2022 - 12/2022)

Calibration and Testing of Medical Devices (09/2022 - 10/2022)

Cyrix Healthcare Pvt. Ltd.

#### LANGUAGES

Malayalam

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Full Professional Proficiency

riench

Elementary Proficiency

### **INTERESTS**

AI in Healthcare

Medical Technology

Literature